<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CPS Lab | Cyber-Phsysical Intelligence</title><link>https://netlabcode.github.io/author/cps-lab/</link><atom:link href="https://netlabcode.github.io/author/cps-lab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>CPS Lab</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://netlabcode.github.io/images/logo.svg</url><title>CPS Lab</title><link>https://netlabcode.github.io/author/cps-lab/</link></image><item><title>AI for Sport</title><link>https://netlabcode.github.io/artificial-intelligence/ai4sport/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netlabcode.github.io/artificial-intelligence/ai4sport/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="artificial-intelligence-for-sport-application">Artificial Intelligence for Sport Application&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Advances in artificial intelligence present new opportunities for enhancing sports performance analysis, injury prevention, and strategic decision-making. This research proposes the development of an AI-powered sports analytics framework leveraging the PySport library for data acquisition, processing, and model integration. The system will apply machine learning techniques to extract actionable insights from player statistics, game events, and performance metrics. Predictive models will be designed for talent scouting, match outcome forecasting, and personalized training recommendations. By combining AI-driven analytics with the flexible data handling capabilities of PySport, the project aims to deliver a versatile and scalable solution that supports coaches, analysts, and athletes in data-informed decision-making.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CWnlGBVaRpQ" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;figure >
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/artificial-intelligence/ai4sport/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" >
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/artificial-intelligence/ai4sport/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="25%" height="980">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>CPS Digital Twin</title><link>https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-physical-system/cpsdigitaltwin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-physical-system/cpsdigitaltwin/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="modelling-cyber-physical-system-digital-twin">Modelling Cyber-Physical System Digital Twin&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cyber-Physical Systems (CPS) require integrated modeling of both operational technology and physical infrastructure to enable accurate monitoring, analysis, and control. This research proposes the development of a CPS Digital Twin that combines network and power system simulation within a unified framework. Mininet will be employed to emulate the operational technology layer, capturing communication patterns, latency, and network topology effects. PandaPower will be used to simulate the electrical power system, enabling detailed modeling of grid components, load flows, and operational states. The cyber and physical domains will be interconnected through the OPC UA protocol, facilitating standardized, secure, and real-time data exchange between simulators. This digital twin framework will support the study of CPS resilience, performance optimization, and the impact of cyber events on physical operations, providing a valuable platform for testing, training, and research in secure, intelligent infrastructure systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-physical-system/cpsdigitaltwin/CPSmodel_hufbd340955497e78b3ebd3b6171e9c080_333124_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" >
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-physical-system/cpsdigitaltwin/CPSmodel_hufbd340955497e78b3ebd3b6171e9c080_333124_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="100%" height="573">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure >
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-physical-system/cpsdigitaltwin/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" >
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-physical-system/cpsdigitaltwin/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="25%" height="980">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Federated Learning IDS</title><link>https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/federatedlearningids/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/federatedlearningids/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="federated-learning-ids">Federated Learning IDS&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="federated-deep-learning-application-for-intrusion-detection-system">Federated Deep Learning Application for Intrusion Detection System.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS) are essential for safeguarding networked environments, yet traditional centralized training approaches for detection models often raise concerns about data privacy, scalability, and adaptability to diverse environments. This research investigates the application of federated deep learning to IDS, enabling multiple entities to collaboratively train robust detection models without sharing raw data. By distributing model training across participating nodes and aggregating only learned parameters, the proposed approach preserves privacy while leveraging diverse, real-world datasets. The study explores architectures optimized for anomaly and signature-based detection, evaluates performance against evolving cyber threats, and assesses resilience to data heterogeneity and poisoning attacks. The ultimate goal is to demonstrate that federated deep learning can deliver high detection accuracy, strong privacy guarantees, and scalable deployment for modern intrusion detection systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The implementation of the proposed federated learning IDS will be evaluated in a controlled Mininet simulation environment. In this setup, network traffic data will be distributed across multiple virtual nodes to mimic real-world decentralized scenarios. Each node will locally train its deep learning model using its own subset of traffic data, ensuring that sensitive information remains within its origin. Model parameters will then be securely aggregated at a central server to produce a global detection model. This deployment approach enables systematic testing of detection performance, communication overhead, and scalability under varying network conditions, while maintaining strict data privacy and simulating realistic operational constraints.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure id="figure-httpslinkspringercomarticle101007s11280-020-00780-4">
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/federatedlearningids/FederatedLearning_huc81d1006d06ac5755bc65c84d0490d6b_62523_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" data-caption="&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11280-020-00780-4&amp;#34;&amp;gt;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11280-020-00780-4&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;">
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/federatedlearningids/FederatedLearning_huc81d1006d06ac5755bc65c84d0490d6b_62523_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="100%" height="557">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>
&lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11280-020-00780-4">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11280-020-00780-4&lt;/a>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure id="figure-">
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/federatedlearningids/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" data-caption="">
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/federatedlearningids/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="25%" height="980">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>MCP</title><link>https://netlabcode.github.io/miscellaneous/mcp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netlabcode.github.io/miscellaneous/mcp/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="model-context-protocol-mcp">Model Context Protocol (MCP)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Model Context Protocol (MCP) is an open-source, vendor-agnostic framework introduced by Anthropic in November 2024 that standardizes how large language models (LLMs) integrate with external tools, data sources, and services. Acting as a universal interface—often likened to a USB-C port for AI—MCP enables developers to build AI applications without gluing together numerous custom integrations, thereby solving the pervasive “N×M” connector problem. With client–server architecture, rich SDK support across languages, and growing adoption by major AI platforms, MCP is poised to become the backbone of scalable, interoperable AI systems. This research will analyze MCP’s architecture, evaluate its effectiveness in facilitating multi-tool LLM workflows, and explore security and usability limitations to support its evolution as a reliable standard in AI integration.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure id="figure-">
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/miscellaneous/mcp/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" data-caption="">
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/miscellaneous/mcp/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="980" height="980">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>NetBeat</title><link>https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/netbeat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/netbeat/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="netbeat-network-traffic-characterization-for-adaptive-anomaly-detection">NetBeat: Network Traffic Characterization for Adaptive Anomaly Detection.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Signature based solutions and supervised classification for anomaly detection struggle to keep pace with evolving cyberattacks because attack behavior is non deterministic and quickly diverges from past labels. NetBeat adopts an unsupervised anomaly detection approach grounded in network traffic characterization that remains effective even when payloads are encrypted. The concept draws on the human heartbeat, where rhythm and pattern reveal anomalies. NetBeat models baseline communication rhythms and detects deviations in real time using metadata that remains observable on encrypted networks, for example packet length sequences, inter arrival timing, burst structure, flow directionality, session duration, and encryption layer signals such as TLS versions, cipher suites, ALPN, and fingerprint features like JA3 or JA4 when available. For QUIC it considers handshake attributes, spin bit behavior, and connection level statistics. The system is designed to remain privacy preserving, since no payload decryption is required, and it is resilient to traffic padding and jitter through robust sequence features and normalization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Methodologically, NetBeat learns seasonal and context aware baselines per host, subnet, and application cohort, then scores departures from those baselines using a combination of statistical change detection and deep sequence models such as autoencoders or transformers on packet and flow time series. Online adaptation handles concept drift without manual retuning. The detector targets behaviors that persist under encryption, including beaconing command and control, lateral movement, covert exfiltration, tunnel misuse, and staging traffic. The design anticipates reduced visibility caused by encrypted client hello and strict content security policies by falling back to purely flow based features and by fusing signals across concurrent flows. Evaluation will use encrypted and mixed traffic traces with red team scenarios and public corpora, and will report time to detection, false positive rate under drift, ROC AUC, and operational cost. The goal is to demonstrate that NetBeat improves adaptability and resilience against unpredictable and emerging threats on modern encrypted networks while maintaining strong privacy guarantees and scalable deployment.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure id="figure-">
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/netbeat/netBeat_hu2f293ca03d6afbb478cb3136fd0ca0d0_110122_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" data-caption="">
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/netbeat/netBeat_hu2f293ca03d6afbb478cb3136fd0ca0d0_110122_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="60%" height="359">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure id="figure-">
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/netbeat/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" data-caption="">
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/netbeat/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="25%" height="980">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>SMS OTP Hardening</title><link>https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/smsotphardening/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/smsotphardening/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="sms-otp-hardening">SMS OTP Hardening&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="enhancing-the-resilience-of-sms-based-one-time-password-systems-against-interception-spoofing-and-social-engineering-attacks-through-protocol-improvements-and-complementary-verification-mechanisms">Enhancing the resilience of SMS-based One-Time Password systems against interception, spoofing, and social engineering attacks through protocol improvements and complementary verification mechanisms.&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>SMS-based One-Time Password (OTP) authentication remains one of the most widely used second-factor security methods due to its simplicity and accessibility. However, it is increasingly vulnerable to evolving attack vectors such as SIM swapping, SS7 protocol exploitation, SMS phishing, and man-in-the-middle interception. This research explores strategies to harden SMS OTP systems without sacrificing usability. Proposed measures include augmenting OTP delivery with cryptographic binding to session metadata, integrating device fingerprinting for contextual verification, and employing adaptive expiration policies based on risk assessment. By combining protocol-level defenses with intelligent anomaly detection, the study aims to significantly raise the difficulty of OTP compromise, thereby extending the viability of SMS-based authentication in modern threat environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure id="figure-source-httpslinkspringercomarticle101007s11276-023-03455-w">
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/smsotphardening/smsOTP_hu20c24ee4bca6054ba8b8a11a7b7fec51_229874_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" data-caption="source: &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11276-023-03455-w&amp;#34;&amp;gt;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11276-023-03455-w&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;">
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/smsotphardening/smsOTP_hu20c24ee4bca6054ba8b8a11a7b7fec51_229874_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="75%" height="840">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>
source: &lt;a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11276-023-03455-w">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11276-023-03455-w&lt;/a>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure id="figure-">
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/smsotphardening/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" data-caption="">
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-security/smsotphardening/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="25%" height="980">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Spatio Temporal AQ</title><link>https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-physical-system/spatiotemporalaq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-physical-system/spatiotemporalaq/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="spatio-temporal-air-quality-prediction-model">Spatio Temporal Air Quality Prediction Model&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Accurate forecasting of air quality is essential for mitigating public health risks and supporting environmental policy decisions. This research proposes the development of a spatio-temporal prediction model that integrates both spatial correlations among monitoring stations and temporal patterns in pollutant variations. By combining historical air quality measurements with meteorological, geographic, and emission source data, the model aims to capture complex dependencies across space and time. Advanced machine learning architectures, such as graph neural networks and recurrent models, will be explored to improve prediction accuracy and robustness. The expected outcome is a predictive framework capable of providing fine-grained, short- and medium-term air quality forecasts, enabling timely interventions and more effective urban air quality management.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9jVTdxDEFxs" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;figure id="figure-source-httpsoizomcomhow-can-air-quality-forecasting-help-reduce-pollution-exposure">
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-physical-system/spatiotemporalaq/oizom_hu35610471211d5d45183859f624536902_330976_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" data-caption="source: &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://oizom.com/how-can-air-quality-forecasting-help-reduce-pollution-exposure/&amp;#34;&amp;gt;https://oizom.com/how-can-air-quality-forecasting-help-reduce-pollution-exposure/&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;">
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-physical-system/spatiotemporalaq/oizom_hu35610471211d5d45183859f624536902_330976_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="100%" height="497">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>
source: &lt;a href="https://oizom.com/how-can-air-quality-forecasting-help-reduce-pollution-exposure/">https://oizom.com/how-can-air-quality-forecasting-help-reduce-pollution-exposure/&lt;/a>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure id="figure-">
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-physical-system/spatiotemporalaq/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" data-caption="">
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/cyber-physical-system/spatiotemporalaq/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="25%" height="980">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>XAI</title><link>https://netlabcode.github.io/artificial-intelligence/xai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://netlabcode.github.io/artificial-intelligence/xai/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="explainable-artificial-intelligence-xai">Explainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The growing adoption of artificial intelligence in critical domains such as healthcare, finance, and cybersecurity demands models that are not only accurate but also transparent and trustworthy. This research aims to develop Explainable AI (XAI) methods that provide clear, interpretable insights into model decision-making without sacrificing performance. By combining model-agnostic explanation techniques with inherently interpretable architectures, the proposed approach seeks to enhance user trust, support regulatory compliance, and facilitate human–AI collaboration. The study will evaluate these methods across multiple application domains, assessing their effectiveness in improving transparency, detectability of bias, and actionable decision support.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;a data-fancybox="" href="https://netlabcode.github.io/artificial-intelligence/xai/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" >
&lt;img data-src="https://netlabcode.github.io/artificial-intelligence/xai/shield_hu419380dd6ff4e0658cd2536e184f1ca5_680159_2000x2000_fit_lanczos_2.png" class="lazyload" alt="" width="25%" height="980">
&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure></description></item></channel></rss>